War Posters Collection
War Posters Collection
1913-1945
265 items
Posters from World War I and World War II. Majority are American but there are a few from Canada, France and England. Subjects include recruitment, fund-raising (war chest, savings bonds, chocolate fund), civil defense, and more. Organizations represented include the Red Cross; U.S. Army, Navy, Air Force and Marine Corps; American Expeditionary Force; various relief committees; more.
2828847
Biographical History
Before the widespread presence of television and radio, and to a lesser extent even after, wartime governments often used posters to broadcast to the civilian population important themes such as civil defense, recruitment, morale-boosting and fund-raising. In many cases notable artists would be engaged to create the illustrations.
World War I and World War II were particularly rich in these cheap and omnipresent pieces of propaganda. According to the Smithsonian Institution's "Produce for Victory: Posters on the American Home Front":
Addressing every citizen as a combatant in the war of production, wartime posters united the power of art with the power of advertising to sell the idea that the factory and the home were also arenas of war. Poster campaigns aimed not only to increase productivity in factories, but also to enlarge people's views of their responsibilities in a time of total war...
[P]eople would encounter posters in places that other media couldn't reach—schools, factories, offices, store windows, and other places outside the scope of paid advertising. Second, posters had democratic appeal—they could be made by anyone; they could be seen by all. Both medium and message spoke of democracy, which made posters ideal for expressing American war aims: why we fight, what we fight for.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The War Posters Collection consists of more than 250 posters from World War I and World War II. Common themes include recruitment, fund-raising (war chest, savings bonds, chocolate fund), civil defense, and morale-boosting. Organizations represented include the Red Cross; U.S. Army, Navy, Air Force and Marine Corps; American Expeditionary Force; various relief committees; and other groups involved directly or indirectly in the war effort.
Of particular interest is a group of 28 World War I posters customized for use in Syracuse and Onondaga County. These items were over-printed with local addresses for recruiting centers and fund-raising organizations, such as the Syracuse and Onondaga County War Chest.
Bibliography
Dulles, Foster Rhea. The American Red Cross: A History. New York: Harper (1950).
Flagg, James Montgomery. James Montgomery Flagg. New York: Watson-Guptill Publications (1974).
Judd, Denis. Posters of World War Two. New York: St. Martin's Press (1973)
National Archives. Powers of Persuasion. Online.
World War I Posters. United States; Great Britain; Canada (1917, 1921)
Smithsonian Institution. Produce for Victory. Online.
Arrangement of the Collection
Posters are subdivided by the war to which they relate. Within that, items have been assigned identification numbers and are arranged in order by number.
Related Material
See also the
Spock Collection of War Posters
(World War I, World War II, Vietnam).
Subject and Genre Headings
Military history; New York State; Aderente, Vincent, approximately 1880-1941.; Babcock, Richard Fayerweather.; Baker, Ernest Hamlin, 1889-1975.; Barney, Maginel Wright, 1877-1966.; Beall, C. C. (Cecil Calvert), 1892-1967.; Beneker, Gerrit A. (Gerrit Albertus), 1882-1934.; Christy, Howard Chandler, 1873-1952.; Coffin, Haskell, 1878-1941.; Cox, Allyn, 1896-1982.; Cox, Kenyon, 1856-1919.; Davies, Roland.; Daugherty, James, 1889-1974.; Downe, Albro F.; Fisher, Harrison, 1875-1934.; Flagg, James Montgomery, 1877-1960.; Forsythe, Vic, 1885-1962.; Grant, Gordon, 1875-1962.; Harris, Lawrence S.; Illian, George, 1894-1932.; Jacobs, Leonebel.; Kline, Hibberd V. B. (Hibberd Van Buren), 1885-; Leyendecker, J. C. (Joseph Christian), 1874-1951.; Matthews, Harry B.; Paus, Herbert Andrew, 1880-1946.; Pennell, Joseph, 1857-1926.; Raemaekers, Louis, 1869-1956.; Reuterdahl, Henry, 1871-1925.; Roeg, Herman.; Riesenberg, Sidney H.; Ruttan, Charles E.; Shafer, L. A. (Leon Alaric), 1866-1940.; Shahn, Ben, 1898-1969.; Smith, Daniel V.; Spear, Gil.; St. John, James Allen, 1872-1957.; Strothmann, F. (Frederick), 1872-; Treidler, Adolph, b. 1886.; Tornrose, Axel Townsend.; Verrees, J. Paul, b. 1889.; Whitehead, Walter, 1874-1956.; Williams, J. Scott (John Scott), 1877-1975.; Woodburn, Thomas.; American Red Cross -- Posters.; United States. -- Army. -- Air Service -- Posters.; United States. -- Army. -- American Expeditionary Forces -- Posters.; United States. -- Army -- Posters.; United States. -- Navy -- Posters.; United States. -- Marine Corps -- Posters.; Liberty bonds -- Posters.; Recruiting and enlistment -- Posters.; War posters, American.; War posters, British.; War posters, Canadian.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Posters.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Posters.; Onondaga County (N.Y.) -- History.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- History.; Posters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Original collection, unspecified.
Onondaga County posters were purchased with funds from the Syracuse Library Associates, 2010, and from the Adah C. Blackman Fund.
Four additional items added, 2017, source unknown.
Inventory
- World War I
  - Give to the American Chocolate Fund for US Forces In France / Send Subscriptions to 4 West 57th St Depository – Equitable Trust Co. Colonial Branch, undated; WWI-1; 70 cm / 52.5 cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Type: American Chocolate Fund
    Artist: Dot King
    Printer: Sackett & Wilhelm Corp., NY
    Condition: Small hole in center, small tear bottom edge, tear on right edge
  - A.E.F. to the President "If the folks back home fall short on the billions you need, Mr. President, call on us for the balance. We like our pay – but if we have to we can go without it. Yours for victory, A.E.F. France, Sept. 7, 1918, 4th Liberty Loan, Sept. 1918(?); WWI-2; 76.5cm / 51cm black, white, red (Map-case 51)
    Type: American Expeditionary Force
    Description: Sketch of soldier
    Artist: C. Le Roy Baldridge, Private, Infantry, on duty with the Stars & Stripes, official publication of the A.E.F.
    Printer: Robert Gair Company, Brooklyn, NY
    Condition: VERY DAMAGED – center top half taped together, tears along all for edges
  - We Need You, 1913; WWI-3; 102cm / 76cm black, white, red (Map-case 51)
    Type: American Red Cross
    Description: Nurse in Red Cross Uniform
    Artist: Albert Ste(?)
    Printer: American Lithographic Co., NY
    Condition: Some fraying and ripping around edges
  - What Can You Do? Join Our Red Cross; Membership Including Red Cross Magazine, undated; WWI-4; 107cm / 70.5cm red, white, black (Map-case 51)
    Description: Red cross woman with soldier & mother & children
    Artist: n/a
    Printer: n/a
    Condition: Folds and small tears along the upper portion
  - What Are You Doing to Help?; Join Your American Red Cross, undated; WWI-5; 96.5cm / 63.5cm red, white, black (Map-case 51)
    Description: Charcoal drawing of a Red Cross nurse leading a wounded soldier
    Artist: Thordon Grant
    Condition: Tears along all four edges
  - Help Your American Red Cross, undated; WWI-6; 105.5cm / 76cm red, white, some color (Map-case 51)
    Description: Nurse on battlefield with wounded soldier, Red Cross ambulance, explosions
    Condition: Very poor, many tears all over
  - Hold Up Your End! War Fund Week; One Hundred Million Dollars, undated; WWI-7; 52cm / 75cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Artist: W.B. King
    Condition: Upper right corner missing, large tear along bottom edge, many small tears on other edges
  - 10,000,000 Members by Christmas; On Christmas Eve a Candle in Every Window & Red Cross Members in Every Home, undated; WWI-8; 76cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Christmas candle in Window with Red Cross
    Condition: Large tear in top edge, no other damage
  - Invaded But Not Conquered, undated; WWI-9; 63.5cm / 45.5cm black, white, red (Map-case 51)
    Description: Woman tied to a post
    Artist: Allyn Cox
    Condition: no damage
  - Boy Scouts of America Weapons for Liberty, undated; WWI-10; 2 copies 55cm / 67cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Type: Boy Scouts of America
    Description: Boy Scouts
    Artist: Leyendecker
    Condition: Copy 1 – VERY DAMAGED, several areas are missing; Copy 2 – some damage, tears along edges
  - Come Into the Ranks & Fight For Your King & Country – Don't Stay in the Crowd & Stare / You are at the Front – Enlist To-Day, undated; WWI-11; 94cm / 62cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Type: British Recruitment Poster
    Description: Group of men is suits watching the army march by, British flag flying in between them
    Printer: Parliamentary Recruiting Committee, London
    Condition: Tears, taped along the back, wrinkled
  - Empire's Need Men Munitions Money / Which Are You Supplying?, undated; WWI-12; 62.5cm / 46.5cm red, white, blue (Map-case 51)
    Description: British flag on top
  - 'Send More Men' Won't You Answer the Call?, undated; WWI-13; 92.5cm / 63cm blue, brown with white lettering (Map-case 51)
    Type: Canadian Recruitment Poster
    Description: WWI soldiers speaking into phone
    Printer: Stone Ltd. (Publishing)
  - 4 Questions to Men Who Have Not Enlisted... Your King & Country Need You / Enlist To-Day / God save the king and the boys!, undated; WWI-14; 107cm / 71cm red, white, blue (Map-case 51)
    Description: Includes four questions to men
    Condition: Section torn off at top left corner, tears along both right and left edges
  - Canada appeals to the Patriotism of her sons / Recruits Wanted for Overseas Battalions... (list of wages)..., undated; WWI-15; 65.5cm / 48cm red, white, blue (Map-case 51)
    Printer: Imp. "Le Soeil"
    Condition: Board – fraying around edges, some moisture damage
  - Nous Defendrons le precieux joyau de la Liberte Le tambour bat, le clarion sonne; Qui reste en arrieve... Personne! Ce'st un peuple qui se defend. En avant! Aiderons – Nous A Ecraser La Tyrannie? S'adresser au Bureau d Recrutement, undated; WWI-16; 94.5cm / 62.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Soldier in uniform between to British flags
    Printer: Gazette Printing Co. Limited, Montreal, Canada
    Condition: Board is cracked on lower left corner, moisture damage on right edge
  - Heroes of St. Julien & Festubert (poem) / Shall We Follow Their Example? / Apply At Recruiting Station, undated; WWI-17; 94.5cm / 62.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Soldier standing before a British flag
    Condition: Left corner missing, moisture damage on right edge
  - Canadiens – Francais! Le Prussien est encore sur le sol de France / Et la FRANCE est notre ancienne MERE-PATRIE / Nirez-vous pas combattre aux cotes de ses Heroiques Soldats / L'Association Civile de Recrutement du District de Quebec, undated; WWI-18; 71.5cm / 50.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Soldiers marching together
    Condition: Large tears around edges
  - Les Allies Ont Besoin D'Hommes Sir William Price vent leur en fournir / Pourquoi ne pas aller avec lui? Que vous dis votre conscience? / Si vous pouvez partir, ne donnez aucune excuse et enrolez vous dans les / CARABINIERS DE QUEBEC / 171e Battalion d'Outre-Mer / Quartiers Generaux: 72 ½ rue St. Pierre on YMCA, undated; WWI-19; 82.5cm / 59.5cm Yellow, black, white (Map-case 51)
    Description: Man in front of ship saying "Pourquoi ne venez-vous pas?"
    Printer: Chronicle Print
    Condition: Slight fraying at edges
  - Canadiens – Francais Enrolez-vous! Notre Premiere Ligne De Defense Est En France. / N'Attendez pas pour defendre notre pays qu'il soit envahi, devaste. / Epargnez Ces Horreurs a Ceux qui vous sont chers / Le Coeur de la France saigne. La voix du sang parle. / N'oubliez pas, Canadiens – Francais, que vous etes descendants des compagnons de Dollard, des soldats de Montclam & de Levis; les fils des vainqueurs de Chateauquay et les freres des heros de St. Julien & de Festubert. / REFORMEZ LES REGIMENTS DE VOLTIGEURS DE SALABE(?), undated; WWI-20; 104cm / 68.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Two soldiers standing together
    Condition: VERY DAMAGED – many sections missing, moisture damage on right side
  - Liberte... Liberte Cheri... Conduis Southiens Nos Bras Vengeurs, undated; WWI-21; 50cm / 76cm red, white, black (Map-case 51)
    Type: Free French Press & Information
    Description: Victory & the Statue of Liberty
    Artist: Nathan Carlee
    Printer: Free French Press & Information Service, New York
  - Our Daddy is Fighting at the Front for YOU – Back Him Up – / Buy a U.S. Government Bond of the 2nd Liberty Loan of 1917, WWI-22; 76.5cm / 51cm red, white, blue (Map-case 51)
    Type: Government Bonds
    Description: Two children waving US flags
    Artist: Dewey
    Printer: T.F. Moore Co. New York
  - My Soldier (prayer) Buy US Government Bonds – Third Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-23; 106.5cm / 71cm red, white, blue, black (Map-case 51)
    Description: Mother & child saying a prayer before bedtime
    Condition: Large tear on left edge, small tears along all edges
  - "time has come to conquer or submit" / "For us there is but one choice. We have made it" / Woodrow Wilson, undated; WWI-24; --- brown, red, white, blue (Map-case 51)
    Description: Portrait of Woodrow Wilson with American flags
    Printer: American Lithographic Company
    Condition: Small tear top edge
  - President Wilson to the People of the Untied States... (letter follows) / To-day buy that bond, undated; WWI-25; 82cm / 56.5cm black, white (Map-case 51)
    Description: Letter from President Wilson
    Condition: Edges are fraying
  - Ring It Again Buy US Government Bonds / Third Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-26; 76.5cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Liberty bell & colonial city scene
    Condition: Holes along edges and large tear in bottom left hand corner
  - Ring It Again Buy US Government Bonds / Third Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-27; 75cm / 47.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Liberty Bell & Colonial city scene
    Condition: Damage along upper edge
  - Halt the Hun! Buy US Government Bonds / Third Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-28; 2 copies 75cm / 50.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: US Soldier stopping enemy from hurting mother & child
    Artist: Raleigh
    Condition: Both copies – Minor damage, few tears along edges
  - Over the Top For You / Buy US Government Bonds / Third Liberty Union, undated; WWI-29; 2 copies 76.5cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Soldier running with American flag
    Artist: Sidney H. Riesenberg
    Printer: Ketterlinus, Phila.
    Condition: Copy 1 – no damage Copy 2 – Some tears on edges
  - Remember! The Flag of Liberty Support It! / Buy US Government Bonds / 3rd Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-30; 2 copies copy 1 – 76cm / 51cm;copy 2 – 73.5cm / 48.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Immigrant family in front of ships & US flag
    Printer: Heywood Strasser & Voight Litho. Co., NY
    Condition: Copy 1 – no damage Copy 2 – Some tears at edges, Portioned taped at top edge
  - "Good-Bye, Dad, I'm Off To Fight For Old Glory, / You Buy US Government Bonds" / Third Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-31; 3 copies 76.5cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Father shaking son's (soldier's) hand with farm in background
    Artist: Lawrence Harris
    Condition: Copy 1 – no damage; Copy 2 – Damaged edges, taped down back of top half; Copy 3 – Large tear on the top edge
  - Come On! Buy More Liberty Bonds, 1918; WWI-32; 3 copies Copies 1 and 2 – 76.5cm / 51cm; copy 3 – 68cm / 49cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Type: Liberty Bonds
    Description: Soldier with bayonet on battlefield
    Artist: Walter Whitehead
    Printer: Ketterlinus Phila.
    Condition: Copies 1&2 – Small tears on edges Copy 3 – Large tear on bottom edge
  - The Hun – his Mark Blot it Out with Liberty Bonds, undated; WWI-33; 74cm / 50.5cm black, white, red (Map-case 51)
    Description: Red (blood) handprint
    Artist: J. Allen St. John
    Printer: Manz Engraving Co., Chi.
    Condition: Major damage and fading
  - The Hun – his Mark Blot it our with Liberty Bonds, undated; WWI-34; 76.5cm / 51cm black, white, red (Map-case 51)
    Description: Red (blood) hand print
    Printer: Manz Engraving Co. Chi.
  - Beat the Hun Back with Liberty Bonds, undated; WWI-35; 3 copies 76.5cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Hun with bloodied knife & hands
    Artist: F. Strothmann
    Condition: Copy 1 – no damage Copies 2&3 – some tears and folds on edges
  - Buy Liberty Bonds / "That Government of the People, by the People, For the People shall not perish from the earth" A. Lincoln, undated; WWI-36; brown / tan tones (Map-case 51)
    Description: Image of Lincoln in center
  - Must Children Die & Mothers Plead in Vain? / Buy More LIBERTY BONDS, undated; WWI-37; 2 copies copy 1 – 102.5cm / 76.5cm; copy 2 – 95.5cm / 72.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Mother pleading, surrounded by her children
    Printer: Sackett & Wilhelm Corporation, NY
    Condition: Many torn edges on both copies
  - That Liberty Shall Not Perish From the Earth / Buy Liberty Bonds Fourth Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-38; 84cm / 55.5cm sepia shades (Map-case 51)
    Description: Statue of Liberty being bombed
    Artist: Joseph Pennell
    Printer: Alco-Gravure, Inc., NY
    Condition: Small tear on right edge
  - That Liberty Shall Not Perish From The Earth / Buy Liberty Bonds Fourth Liberty Loan, undated; WWI-39; 105cm / 76.5cm white, black, orange, brown (Map-case 51)
    Description: Image of the Statue of Liberty burning
    Printer: Ketterlinus Phila, IMP
    Condition: Large tears on right and top sides
  - Hun or Home? Buy More Liberty Bonds, undated; WWI-40; 76cm / 50.5cm black, brown, red (Map-case 51)
    Description: Mother holding child with figure looming in background
    Printer: Edwards & Deutsch Litho Co. Chicago
  - Keep These Off The USA / Buy More Liberty Bonds, undated; WWI-41; 102cm / 77.5cm black, white, red (Map-case 51)
    Description: Pair of bloodied cowboy boots
    Artist: John Norton
    Printer: Strobridge Litho Co. Cincinnati & New York
    Condition: Tears along the edges, upper left corner missing
  - In Belgium Help / The National Committee for Relief in Belgium, undated; WWI-42; 98.5cm / 60.5cm black, white, red, yellow, orange (Map-case 51)
    Type: National Committee for Relief in Belgium
    Description: Mother in red holding on to child
    Artist: Louis Raemaekers
    Condition: Tear on upper right side
  - What Are You Doing? The Kaiser Is Canned – Can Food /, 1918; WWI-43; 84cm / 56cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Type: National War Garden Commission
    Description: Kaiser in a jar labeled "Kaiser Brand Unsweetened"
    Artist: J. Paul Verrees
  - Women Of America Work for Victory / Write for Free Book to National War Garden Commission, 1918; WWI-44; 56cm / 35.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Woman in red, white, & blue with garden products
    Artist: Leonebel Jacobs
    Printer: F.M. Lupton, Publisher's (inc.)
  - Seeds of Victory Insure the Fruits of Peace / For Free Book Write to National War Garden Commission, 1919; WWI-45; 74.5cm / 58.5cm Color: multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Young girl with marching vegetables
    Artist: Maginel Wright Enright
  - War Gardens over the Top / The Seeds of Victory Insure the Fruits of Peace / (Address & officials), 1919; WWI-46; 74.5cm / 59cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Young girl & vegetables climbing over a hill
  - Women of Britain Say "Go!", Mar 1915; WWI-47; 76.5cm / 50.5cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Type: Parliamentary Recruiting Committee
    Description: Women watching soldiers march to war
    Printer: Hill, Siffken & Co. (L.P.A.), Graftom Works, London
  - Daddy, what did YOU do for the Great War?, undated; WWI-48; 76.5cm / 51cm multicolor (Map-case 51)
    Description: Father Sitting, daughter on lap, son playing with toy soldiers
    Artist: Johnson, Riddle & Co., Ltd., London
    Printer: Johnson, Riddle & Co., Ltd. London
  - Won't You Equip My Substitute while I'm fighting Over There?, undated; WWI-49; 108cm / 50.5cm multi (Map-case 51)
    Type: Police Field Days
    Description: Police officer & soldier standing by each other
    Artist: Horrison Troyor
    Condition: Tears on top and bottom edges
  - Answer the Call, Fall In, Don't You Hear the Bugle Calling? / Join Quebec, The Rifles 171st, undated; WWI-50; 83cm / 60cm Yellow, black, white (Map-case 51)
    Type: Quebec Rifles
    Description: Soldier playing a bugle
    Condition: Large break along the backside of the board – fragile!
  - Tipperary – It's a Long, Long Way To Tipperary / Sung By Soldiers of the King, undated; WWI-51; 64.5cm / 53cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Type: Tipperary
    Description: Made of cotton & shows song & music
    Artist: B. Feldman & Co.
    Printer: Messrs. B. Feldman & Co. Arthur Street London WC
  - Caption: Columbia Calls – Enlist Now for U.S. Army Nearest Recruiting Station, 1916; WWI-52; 102cm / 76cm multicolor (Map-case 52)
    Type: U.S. Army
    Description: Poem by Frances Adams Halsted "Columbia Calls"
    Artist: Designed by Frances Adams Halsted; painted by V. Aderente
    Condition: Some small tears along the right side, one large tear along the bottom of the right side
  - I Want YOU for the US Army / Nearest Recruiting Station, 1917; WWI-53; 102cm / 76cm (2 Copies) red, white, blue (Map-case 52)
    Description: Uncle Sam pointing his finger
    Artist: James Montgomery Flagg
    Printer: Leslie-Judge Co. NY
    Condition: Both copies have tears and pieces missing from their edges
  - Feed A Fighter, Eat only what you need –, undated; WWI-54; 74.5cm / 53cm red, white, black (Map-case 52)
    Type: U.S. Food Administration
    Description: Soldiers in trenches
    Artist: W. Morgan
    Printer: Strobridge Lith. Co. Cincinnati & New York
  - HUNGER - For three years America has fought starvation in Belgium, undated; WWI-55; 74cm / 53.5cm black, white, red (Map-case 52)
    Description: Mother & children
  - Sir – Don't waste while your wife saves / Adopt the doctrine of the clean plate ~ Do your share, undated; WWI-56; 74cm / 53.5cm black, white, red (Map-case 52)
    Description: Man eating a meal with waiters behind him
    Artist: Crawford Sounm
    Printer: W.F. Powers Co. Litho, NY
  - Rally 'Round the Flag with U.S. Marines, 1916; WWI-57; 103cm / 77cm red, white (Map-case 52)
    Type: U.S. Marine Corps
    Description: Soldiers on beach with American flag & guns
    Condition: Tears along edges, large tear on right bottom edge
  - First to Fight / "Democracy's Vanguard", 1917; WWI-58; 102cm / 76.5cm black, white, gray (Map-case 52)
    Description: Soldiers running onto the beach
    Artist: Sidney H. Riesenburg
    Condition: Some color changes (molding?) on bottom half and along upper left corner
  - Tell that to the Marines! At 22 Tremont Row, undated; WWI-59; 102cm / 76cm red, white, blue (Map-case 52)
    Type: U.S. Marines Corps
    Description: Man removing suit coat
    Condition: Two large tears along right edge, small tears along left edge, some discoloration along bottom half
  - Teufel Hunden German Nickname for US Marines, undated; WWI-60; 71.5cm / 48.5cm Orange, black, white (Map-case 52)
    Description: Bulldog chasing another dog
    Artist: H